Thomas Raddatz

Full Stack Ruby on Rails Developer

tnraddatz@email.wm.edu | (540) 273–0338 | Fairfax, Virginia

Education

The College of William & Mary

August 2014 - May 2018

Bachelor of Computer Science, B.B.A. in Finance, Accounting Concentration

Cumulative GPA: 3.6

Dean's List: Fall 2014 – Spring 2018; Distinguished Finance Student

George Mason University

August 2013 - May 2014

Computer Science and Finance

Summary

As an Applications Developer at CGI Federal, I work in the International Diplomacy, Assistance and Commerce (IDAC) business unit. In this role, I develop and maintain a suite of CGI Federal products, including the **Momentum financial reporting software**. I support the implementation and ongoing maintenance of Momentum for multiple Federal clients and was recognized by my team lead for receiving the first **5 star consultant review** of all new technical hires.

A recent graduate of The **College of William & Mary** with a **double major** in Computer Science and Finance, I specialize in application and full-stack web development, with an interest in financial technology software. Throughout my four years at the College of William & Mary, I was an avid **Ruby on Rails developer**, building rails applications to compete in hack-a-thons and websites to support the William and Mary Mason School of Business Investment Club and Robotics Club. Both of these clubs I supported in a multifaceted manner. I served as a **Senior Analyst** within the **Investment Club**, presenting at Ivy League stock pitch competitions around the country as well as competing in schoolwide business competitions. Further, I was voted the **Vice President** of the **Robotics Club** my junior year and managed projects in cooperation with the physics department.

Ruby on Rails Experience

Since graduating, I have continued my passion for **Ruby on Rails** and in an effort to encapsulate some of my knowledge into one project, I created "NewSpeak." NewSpeak makes navigating the news easier. With over 20+ News outlets and 10,000+ articles, the application delivers up-to-date news every 15 minutes allowing users to view articles from multiple angles. The application was written on a **Linux OS**, with **Docker** and deployed on **Digital Ocean**, with **agile methodologies** in mind. Each controller and model were developed in a **test driven development environment**, using **rspec and capybara**. The application also employs **ELK stack** and **Lograge** to log data in a sensible way, allowing for the data to be visualized and exported in JSON and csv files. For further information about the JavaScript libraries, configurations and services implemented visit <u>Github</u>.

Key Skills

- Ruby on Rails Development
- Client Relationship
- Ruby, CSS, Bootstrap

- Development Lifecycle
- Testing
- 3rd Party API Integration
- Financial Strategy
- Presentation
- Design

Technical Skills

- OS: Window, Linux
- Other Skills: Python, C++, Java
- Version Control: Git
- Database: PostgreSQL
- Testing: Minitest, Rspec, Capybara

- Tools: Docker, Digital Ocean, Kibana
- Logging: ELK Stack, Lograge
- Tracking: Jira, Bitbucket
- Android: Hybrid Mobile Application Testing
- Projects: Robotics, Web scraping, VR, Finance

Professional Experience

CGI Federal, Fairfax Virginia

September 2018 - Present

Application Developer, Consultant

- Support on-site project teams with new implementations and upgrades by providing them application development and testing services, as well as issue analysis and resolution
- Develop testing scripts to execute user commands through selenium to recreate a functional test
- Communicate with clients to ensure the functionality of features match their requirements

Android Hybrid Application Testing, The College of William & Mary

August – December 2017

Distinguished Software Engineering Course

- Our team was selected to continue work on an existing software base that was maintained by graduate students. The software aimed to deliver automated testing for hybrid mobile applications
- Used test driven development to fix underlying problems within the software, extend its use outside of the example application and develop a GUI to establish an excellent user experience
- Completed all recommended tasks and demonstrated the application to the class and professors at the end of the semester

UltiGesture LLC, Williamsburg Virginia

May - July 2016

Consultant

- Placed 2nd in Business Model Competition and was subsequently hired by the C.S. Graduate Program Director to aid the development of a consumer-oriented smart watch
- Worked as a researcher alongside William & Mary Computer Science PhD students and professors
- Submitted a report, recommending a product, target market and price based on customer data

Generation Code, Vienna Virginia

Summer 2017 - 2018

Teacher

- Taught C++, Python, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS to middle and high school students, emphasizing programming logic and computational thinking
- Focused on a "learn by doing" approach to teaching students in order to spark their interest in computer science